Preliminary Inventory to the Rosika Schwimmer Papers, 1914-1937
Hoover Institution Archives
Rosika Schwimmer Papers,
1914-1937
37005
Schwimmer, Rosika, 1877-1948
2 manuscript boxes, 1 envelope 0.9 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, petitions, clippings, printed matter, and photographs, relating to the pacifist movement during World War I, the Henry Ford Peace Expedition, the International Congress of Women, and the presentation of the World Peace Prize to R. Schwimmer in 1937
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1937.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Henry Ford Peace Expedition; International Congress of Women; Pacifism; Peace; Women; World War, 1914-1918; World War, 1914-1918--Peace; Hungary; United States--Foreign relations
Container List
- Chronological file of correspondence and other material
  - June - July 1914 (Box 1.)
  - August 1914
  - September 1914
  - October 1914
  - November 1914
  - December 1914
  - January 1915
  - February 1915
  - March 1915
  - April 1915
  - May 1915
  - June - July, September 1915
  - October 1915
  - November 1915
  - December 1915
  - January 1916
  - February 1916
  - March - April 1916
  - June 1916
  - July - August 1916
  - December 1916
  - January 1917
  - February 1917
  - March 1917
  - September 1917
  - October 1917
  - December 1917
  - January 1918 (Box 2.)
  - October 1918
  - November 1918
  - December 1918
  - 1920
  - October 1921
  - October - November 1922, August 1923
  - April - May, October 1924
  - January, March - July, September - December 1925
  - January - February, June, August - October, December 1926
  - January, March - April, June - December 1927
  - 1928
  - 1929
  - 1930
  - 1931
  - 1932
  - 1933
  - 1935
- Documentary material concerning Rosika Schwimmer vs. William Fox and Upton Sinclair, 1931-1935
- Woman Patriot Corporation's petition against the admittance of Dr. Albert Einstein to the U.S., 1933
- Swedish cartoon, Queen of Sweden with Crown of Schrapnal appearing in the Swedish periodical Naggen, 1915
- Three postcard reproductions of a poster entitled Stop the War in English and Hungarian; also 6 photographic reproductions of paintings by Giovanni Constantini, depicting the horrors of war
- Collection of miscellaneous data concerning the presentation of the World Peace Prize to Rosika Schwimmer, Dec. 4, 1937